Started at 2019-08-16 11:48:40
cmboxpgm has Version 6.50.2624.500

 
 Help Topic: Product Item Options
 --------------------------------
 This section describes the various options related to Product Item Options 
 (abbreviated PIO).
 
 Product Item commands are structured in the following way:
    /f<Firm Code> [...] /p<Product Code>[...] [<PIO Options>] <Main Command>
 
 The following options are available:

   /p -- Product Code
      Defines the Product Code to be used. Expects an unsigned decimal value as
      argument. Optionally, the item reference or the Feature Code can be 
      specified as further selection parameters. The item reference value must
      be enclosed in square brackets.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /p<value>[=<new value>][:<Feature Code>|<reference>][,<TVB dep.>]
      
      Examples:
      - Select the first Product Item with PC=13
         /p13
      - Select the Product Item with PC=13, Feature Map = 0x00000001
         /p13:0x00000001
      - Select the Product Item with PC=13, item reference = 16
         /p13:[16]
   /papwd -- Access Password
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Access Password PIO.
      Accepts a text as password argument.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /papwd:"<character string>"[,<TVB dep.>]
         /papwd[\"<character string>\"][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified access password.
   /pat -- Activation Time
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Activation Time PIO.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pat-|[a<date>|r<offset>][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets an (a)bsolute or a (r)elative time.
   /pata -- Activation Time, absolute
      Sets the activation time to the specified absolute value. Expects a date
      optionally followed by a time and the time zone as argument. If the time
      zone is omitted, the system's time zone will be used instead.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pata<yyyy><month><dd>[,<hh>:<mm>:<ss>
         [PST|MST|CST|EST|UTC|CET|EET][,<TVB dep.>]
         /pata<yyyy>-<mm>-<dd>[T<hh>:<mm>:<ss>[Z|±hh:mm|±hhmm|±hh]][,<TVB 
      dep.>]
      Examples:
         /pata2013May31,23:59:59UTC
         /pata2013-05-31T23:59:59Z
   /patr -- Activation Time, relative
      Adds the specified number of days to the current activation time. If the
      PIO doesn't exist yet, the current system time plus the specified offset
      will be set as activation time. Expects an integer value greater than or
      equal to zero as argument.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /patr<days>[,<TVB dep.>]
   /pcoli -- Customer Owned License Information
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Customer Owned License 
      Information (COLI). Accepts a text (up to 256 characters) enclosed in 
      double quote character escape sequences as argument.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pcoli-
         /pcoli:"<character string>"[,<TVB dep.>]
         /pcoli[\"<character string>\"][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified text.
   /ped -- Extended Protected Data
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Extended Protected Data PIO.
      Expects a sequence of hexadecimal digits (up to 256 bytes) preceded by 0x
      as argument.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /ped<extended type>-|[:0x<hex data>][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified data.
   /pet -- Expiration Time
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Expiration Time PIO.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pet-|[a<date>|r<offset>][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets an (a)bsolute or a (r)elative time.
   /peta -- Expiration Time, absolute
      Sets the Expiration Time to the specified absolute value. Expects a date
      optionally followed by a time and the time zone as argument. If the time
      zone is omitted, the system's time zone will be used instead.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /peta<yyyy><month><dd>[,<hh>:<mm>:<ss>
         [PST|MST|CST|EST|UTC|CET|EET][,<TVB dep.>]
         /peta<yyyy>-<mm>-<dd>[T<hh>:<mm>:<ss>[Z|±hh:mm|±hhmm|±hh]][,<TVB 
      dep.>]
      Examples:
         /peta2013May31,23:59:59UTC
         /peta2013-05-31T23:59:59Z
   /petr -- Expiration Time, relative
      Adds the specified number of days to the current expiration time. If the
      PIO doesn't exist yet, the current system time plus the specified offset
      will be set as activation time. Expects an integer value greater than or
      equal to zero as argument.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /petr<days>[,<TVB dep.>]
   /pfm -- Feature Map
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Feature Map PIO. Expects an 
      unsigned decimal or a hexadecimal value preceded by 0x as argument.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pfm-|[<value>][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified Feature Map.
   /phd -- Hidden Data
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Hidden Data PIO. Expects an 
      extended type ID as argument. Either the access code or a data section 
      can be specified.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /phd<ext. type>[,<acc. code>][:0x<hex data>][,<TVB dep.>]
            Fills the Hidden Data PIO with user defined data.
         /phd<ext. type>[,<acc. code>][:r<count>][,<TVB dep.>]
            Fills the Hidden Data PIO with <count> bytes of random data.
         /phd<ext. type>-
            Removes the PIO.
   /plq -- License Quantity
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's License Quantity. Accepts an
      unsigned decimal value as argument. Also permissions for network access 
      can be specified. The following predefined configurations are supported:
         'default' : sets default permissions
         'local'   : permits only local usage (Universal Licenses only)
         'red'     : sets permissions for Triple Mode Redundancy usage
         'wan'     : sets permissions for CmWAN usage
      When a License Quantity is newly set up for Triple Mode Redundancy a 
      license tag has to be specified additionally. As license tag argument an
      integer value greater than zero preceded by the # character is expected.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /plq-|[a|r][<counter>][:<access permissions>][[:]#<license tag>][,<TVB
      dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified License Quantity.
      Examples:
      - Setup for 100 network licenses
         /plq100
      - Setup for 100 network licenses and CmWAN
         /plq100:wan
      - Setup for 100 network licenses and Triple Mode Redundancy, license tag
      42
         /plq100:red#42
   /plqa -- License Quantity, absolute
      Sets the Product Item's License Quantity to the given absolute value. 
      Accepts an unsigned decimal value as argument. Also permissions for 
      network access can be specified. The following predefined configurations
      are supported:
         'default' : sets default permissions
         'local'   : permits only local usage (Universal Licenses only)
         'red'     : sets permissions for Triple Mode Redundancy usage
         'wan'     : sets permissions for CmWAN usage
      When a License Quantity is newly set up for Triple Mode Redundancy a 
      license tag has to be specified additionally. As license tag argument an
      integer value greater than zero preceded by the # character is expected.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /plqa[:]<counter>[:<access permissions>][[:]#<license tag>][,<TVB 
      dep.>]
      Examples:
      - Setup for 100 network licenses
         /plqa100
      - Setup for 100 network licenses and CmWAN
         /plqa100:wan
      - Setup for 100 network licenses and Triple Mode Redundancy, license tag
      42
         /plqa100:red#42
   /plqr -- License Quantity, relative
      Increments or decrements the Product Item's License Quantity by the given
      value. Accepts an signed decimal value as argument. Also permissions for
      network access can be specified. The following predefined configurations
      are supported:
         'default' : sets default permissions
         'local'   : permits only local usage (Universal Licenses only)
         'red'     : sets permissions for Triple Mode Redundancy usage
         'wan'     : sets permissions for CmWAN usage
      When a License Quantity is newly set up for Triple Mode Redundancy a 
      license tag has to be specified additionally. As license tag argument an
      integer value greater than zero preceded by the # character is expected.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /plqr<signed value>[:<access permissions>][[:]#<license tag>][,<TVB 
      dep.>]
      Examples:
      - Add 100 network licenses
         /plqr100
      - Remove 100 network licenses
         /plqr-100
      - Add 100 network licenses and configure for Triple Mode Redundancy,
        license tag 42
         /plqr100:red#42
   /plt -- Linger Time
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Linger Time. Accepts an 
      unsigned decimal value as argument.
      Syntax:
         /plt-|[<seconds>][,<TVB dep.>]

   /pltdepth -- License Transfer Depth
      Adds or updates the Product Item's license transfer depth. Accepts an 
      unsigned decimal value between 0 and 65535 as argument.
      Syntax:
         /pltdepth[:]<transfer depth>

   /pltltktarg -- License Transfer LTK Targets
      Adds or updates the Product Item's list of LTK transfer targets. Accepts
      a list of 1-28 CmAct IDs.
      Syntax:
         /pltltktarg:<CmAct ID1>[,<CmAct ID 2>[,<CmAct ID3>]]...

   /pltmbp -- Maximum Borrow Period
      Adds or updates the Product Item's maximum borrow period. Expects either
      a time span measured in days or the token 'none' to specify an unlimited
      period as argument.
      Syntax:
         /pltmbp:<time span>|none

   /pltperm -- License Transfer Permission
      Adds or updates the Product Item's license transfer permissions. Expects
      either the token 'none' to deny any permissions or a comma separated list
      of permission tokens as argument.
      Valid combinable permission tokens are:
         'fitransfer' : the Firm Item may be transferred
         'pull'       : the license may be pulled
         'return'     : the license may be returned
      Syntax:
         /pltperm:<permissions>

   /plttarg -- License Transfer Targets
      Adds or updates the Product Item's list of license transfer targets. 
      Accepts a list of 1-28 CmAct IDs.
      Syntax:
         /plttarg:<CmAct ID1>[,<CmAct ID 2>[,<CmAct ID3>]]...

   /plttype -- License Transfer Type
      Adds or updates the Product Item's license transfer type. Accepts one of
      the following transfer type tokens as argument:
         'none'               : no transfer allowed
         'movecomplete'       : move complete license
         'moveunits'          : move units
         'movelicenses'       : move network licenses
         'borrowlocallicense' : borrow license for local use
         'borrowcomplete'     : borrow complete license
      Syntax:
         /plttype:none|movecomplete|moveunits|movelicenses|borrowlocallicense|b
      orrowcomplete

   /pmer -- Maximum Encryption Rate
      Adds, updates or deletes a Product Item's Maximum Encyption Rate. Expects
      the encryption rate value given as the maximum number of encryptions per
      30 seconds as argument.
      Syntax:
         /pmer-|[<value>][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified value.
   /pmi -- Module Item
      Adds, updates or deletes a Module Item. Expects the Module Item's Product
      Code given as an unsigned decimal value as argument. Optionally, the item
      reference or the Feature Code can be specified as further selection 
      parameters. The item reference value must be enclosed in square brackets.
      Syntax:
         /pmi<Product Code>[:<Feature Code>|<reference>][,<TVB dep.>]
      
      Examples:
      - Select the first Module Item with PC=13
         /pmi13
      - Select the Module Item with PC=13, Feature Map = 0x00000001
         /pmi13:0x00000001
      - Select the Module Item with PC=13, item reference = 16
         /pmi13:[16]
   /pmp -- Maintenance Period
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Maintenance Period.
      Requires CmContainer firmware 1.18 or higher.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pmp-|[d[<start date>,]<end date>|
         i[<start value>,]<end value>[,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets start and end of a Maintenance Period, either
      given as (d)ates or given as unsigned (i)nteger values.
   /pmpd -- Maintenance Period (dates)
      Adds or updates the Product Item's Maintenance Period.
      Requires CmContainer firmware 1.18 or higher.
      Accepts start date and end date of the period as argument.
      The start date may be omitted. In this case it is set to 2000-01-01 
      00:00:00 UTC.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pmpd[<start time>,]<end time>[,<TVB dep.>]
      Example: /pmpd2010Jul01,00:00:00,2011Jun30,23:59:59
   /pmpi -- Maintenance Period (integer values)
      Adds or updates the Product Item's Maintenance Period.
      Requires CmContainer firmware 1.18 or higher.
      Accepts start and end of the period given as unsigned integer values as 
      argument. The start of the period may be omitted. In this case it is set
      to the value 0.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pmpi[<start value>,]<end value>[,<TVB dep.>]
      Example: /pmpi10,19
   /pmrt -- Minimum CodeMeter Runtime Version
      Adds, updates or deletes the Minimum CodeMeter Runtime Version.
      Accepts a version number consisting of major version, minor version and 
      optionally the build number as argument, e.g. '5.20' or '5.20.1370'.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pmrt-|[<major version>.<minor version>[.<build>]][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified data.
   /pnmu -- Named User License
      Adds, updates or deletes the Named User Product Item Option.
      Accepts a <check mode> specification followed by optional configuration 
      parameters and, depending on the specified mode, (1) either a user name,
      (2) domain and user name or (3) a user-defined text as <text> argument.
      The configuration parameters allow to determine whether the specified 
      text is to be stored as plain text in the CmContainer, too.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pnmu-|:<check mode>[,<configuration options>]:<text>[,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified data.
      Valid check mode specifications are:
         user        : user name
         userdomain  : domain and user name
         userdefined : user-defined text
      Valid configuration options are:
         noplain     : plain text is not to be stored in the CmContainer, 
      default
         plain       : plain text is to be stored in the CmContainer
      Examples:
      - Set user name 'Doe', to be stored as plain text:
         /pnmu:user,plain:"Doe"
      - Set domain 'MyDomain' and user name 'Doe', no to be stored as plain 
      text:
         /pnmu:userdomain,noplain:"MyDomain\\Doe"
   /pnwc -- Network License Counter
      Deprecated, please use option /plq instead (identical syntax).
   /ppd -- Protected Data
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Protected Data PIO.
      Accepts a sequence of hexadecimal digits (up to 256 bytes) preceded by 0x
      as argument.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /ppd-|[0x<hex data>][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified data.
   /psd -- Secret Data
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Secret Data PIO. Expects an 
      extended type ID as argument. A data section can be specified.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /psd<ext. type>[:0x<hex data>][,<TVB dep.>]
            Fills the Secret Data PIO with user defined data.
         /psd<ext. type>[:r<count>][,<TVB dep.>]
            Fills the Secret Data PIO with <count> bytes of random data.
         /psd<ext. type>-
            Removes the PIO.
   /pt -- Product Item Text
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Text PIO. Accepts a character
      string (up to 256 characters) enclosed in double quote characters as 
      argument.
      Syntax:
         /pt-
         /pt:"<character string>"
         /pt\"<character string>\"
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified text.
   /puc -- Unit Counter
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Unit Counter PIO. Accepts an
      unsigned decimal value as argument. Depending on the chosen mode the 
      argument is interpreted as (a)bsolute or (r)elative value.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /puc-|[a<value>|r<value>][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets an (a)bsolute or (r)elative value.
   /puca -- Unit Counter, absolute
      Sets the Product Item's Unit Counter to the specified value. Expects an 
      unsigned decimal value smaller than or equal to 4294967294 as argument.
      For a firmware version prior to 1.18 the maximum value is 16777215.
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /puca<value>[,<TVB dep.>]
   /pucr -- Unit Counter, relative
      Increments the Product Item's Unit Counter by the specified amount. 
      Expects a signed decimal value in the range [-2147483647, 2147483647] as
      argument. For a firmware version prior to 1.18 the range is limited to 
      [-16777215, 16777215].
      Individual Trailing Validation Block (TVB) dependencies may be defined 
      for this PIO:
         d=(d)ata, s=(S)erial Number, u=(U)pdate Counter or none.
      Syntax:
         /pucr<signed value>[,<TVB dep.>]
   /pud -- User Data
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's User Data PIO. Accepts a 
      sequence of hexadecimal digits (up to 256 bytes) preceded by 0x as 
      argument.
      Syntax:
         /pud-|[0x<hex data>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified data.
   /pup -- Usage Period
      Adds, updates or deletes the Product Item's Usage Period PIO.
      Requires CmContainer firmware 1.11 or higher.
      Accepts an integer value greater than or equal to zero as argument. 
      Depending on the chosen mode the argument is interpreted as (a)bsolute or
      (r)relative value.
      Syntax:
         /pup-|[[a|r][:]<days>][,<TVB dep.>]
      Removes the PIO (-) or sets the specified Usage Period.
   /pupa -- Usage Period, absolute
      Sets the length of the Product Item's Usage Period to the given number of
      days. Requires CmContainer firmware 1.11 or higher.
      Accepts an integer value greater than or equal to zero as argument.
      Syntax:
         /pupa[:]<days>[,<TVB dep.>]
   /pupr -- Usage Period, relative
      Extends a Usage Period by the given number of days. If the PIO
      does not exist, yet, a Usage Period of the given length will be added.
      Requires CmContainer firmware 1.11 or higher.
      Accepts an integer value greater than or equal to zero as argument.
      Syntax:
         /pupr[:]<days>[,<TVB dep.>]

   /pwupidata -- WUPI Data
      Adds or removes a sequence of Hidden Data PIOs that are used as WUPI data
      storage.
      New WUPI data storage either can be filled with the contents of a 
      specified file or preset with a user-defined fill byte. In this case the
      size of the WUPI data has to be specified.
      Syntax:
         /pwupidata:[e<ext. type>][,b<block size>][,a<acc. code>]:<file>
            Allocates WUPI Data storage, filled with the contents of file 
      <file>.
         /pwupidata:s<size>[,e<ext. type>][,b<block size>][,a<acc. code>]
         [,f<fill byte>]
            Allocates <size> bytes of WUPI Data storage, initialized with the
            value <fill byte>.
         /pwupidata[:s<size>][,e<ext. type>][,b<block size>]-
            Removes the WUPI Data storage.


cmboxpgm finished at 2019-08-16 11:48:40
